[{"question":"<p><strong>There are 8 green ball, 4 blue balls and 3 white balls in a box. Then 1 greenand 1 blue balls are taken from the box and put away. What is&nbsp; the probability that a blue ball is selected at random from the box?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/13","2\/13","4\/15","3\/15"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student measures a piece of rope and found it was 127m long. If the actual length of the rope was 125m, what waas the percentage error in the measurement ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.6%","1.0%","0.8%","0.16%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>At what rate will the interest on N500 increase to N25 in 5 years reckoning&nbsp; in simple interest ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2 %","1%","4%","5%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 3rd term of an arithmetic progression is 8 and the 7th term is -28. Find the 10th term of the progression.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-43","-164","164","44"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x *y= x-y<sup>2<\/sup>, find the value of (2*3)*5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-25","25","-32","32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Five years ago, a father was 3 times as old as his son. Now, their combined ages amount to 110 years. Thus, the present age of the father is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["75 years","60 years","98 years","80 years"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Mother reduced the quantity of food bought for the family by 10% when she found that the cost of living had increased by 15%. Thus the fractional increase in the family food bill is now<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/12","6\/35","19\/300","7\/200"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a soccer competition in one season, a club had scored the following goals: 2,0,3,3,2,1,4,0,0,5,1,0,2,2,1,3,1,4,1, and 1. The mean, median and mode are respectively.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1,1.8,and1.5","1.8,1.5 and 1","1.8,1 and 1.5","1.5, 1 and 1.8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two triangles have the same area if&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Two sides in one triangle are equal to two sides in the other.","Three sides in one triangle are equal to three sides in the other.","Two angles in one triangle are equal to two angles in the other.","Three angles in one triangle are equal to three angles inn the other."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 25x-1 = 64 (5\/2)<sup>6<\/sup>, then x has the value<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7","4","32","5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The smallest number such that when it is divided by 8 has a remainder of 6 and when it is divided by 9 has a remainder of 7 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["50","70","80","60"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a dealer sells a bicycle for N81 he makes profitof 8%. What did he pay for the bicycle ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N74","N74.52","N75","N75.52"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man and his wife went to buy article costing N400. The woman had 10% of the cost and the man 40% of the remainder. How much did they have altogether.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N216","N200","N184","N144"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a school there are 35 students in class 2A and 40 in 2B. The mean score for class 2A in a Mathematics examination is 60.00 and that for 2B in the paper is 52.5. Find, to one place of decimals, the mean of the combined classes.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["56.5","56.0","56.3","56.2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A set of data contains a total of 130 items which are divided into six groups for display on a pie chart. If one of the groups contains 26 items then the sector representing this group on the pie chart contains an angle x at the centre of the circle where x is <\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","60","70","72"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A pentagon has four of its angles equal. If the size of the fifth angle is 60<sup>0<\/sup>&nbsp;find the size of each of the four equal angles.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60<sup>0<\/sup>","108<sup>0<\/sup>","120<sup>0<\/sup>","150<sup>0<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What will be the value of k so that the equation Kx<sup>2<\/sup> - 4x+1=0 has equal roots ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","4","8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x varies inversely as y, and y varies directly as the square root of z, and z varies directly as 1\/w<sup>2<\/sup>, write down in words how x varies with w.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x varies inversely as w<sup>-1<\/sup>","x varies directly as w<sup>-1<\/sup>","x varies directly as w","x varies inversely as w"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contain 3 apples, r oranges and 3 bananas. What is the probability&nbsp; of selecting a banana and then an apple ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9\/100","9\/10","1\/10","2\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can a committe of 3 women and 4 men be chosen from 6 men and 5 women<\/strong><\/p>","options":["250","25","50","100"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Write down the number 0.0052048 correct to three significant figures.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.005","0.0052","0.00521","0.00520"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Write the decimal number 39 to base 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["110111","100111","111000","110111"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An open rectangular box externally measures 4m x 3m x4m. Find the costs of painting the box eternally if its cost #2.00 to paint one square metre<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N11 6.0","N11 3.00","N11 2.00","#13 6.00"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If Musa scored 75 in Biology instead of 57, his average mark in four subjects would have been 60. What was his total mark ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["200","222","322","122"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sola deposited #150.00 in the bank. At the end of 5 years, the simple interest on the princinpal was #55.00. At what rate per annum was the interest paid ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6.3 3%","8.3 3%","7.32%","7.33%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the 20 terms in an arithmetic progression whose first term is&nbsp; 7 and the last term is 117<\/strong><\/p>","options":["239","1240","1340","1440"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The range of the data k+2,k-3,k+,k-2,k-5,k+3,k-1 and k+6 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10","11","12","13"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area bounded by the curve y =x (2 - x), the x-axis, x=0 and x=2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.25sq.units","133sq.units","0.33sq.units","2.33sq.units"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A trader realizes 10x-X<sup>2<\/sup>naira profit from the salae of x bags of corn. How many bags will give him the maximum profit ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","4","3","5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cinema hall contains a certain number&nbsp; of people. If 22.5% are children 47.5% are men and 84 are women, find the number of men in the hall.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["133","132","130","123"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An arc of a circle subtends an angle of 30 on the circumference of a circle of radius 21cm. Find the length of the arc.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11cm","22cm","66cm","44cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of a set of six numbers is 60. If the mean of the first five is 50, find the sixth number in the set.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100","120","105","110"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of the interior angles of a regular polygon is 1800<sup>0<\/sup>. Calculate the size of one exterior angle of the polygon.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["45<sup>-1<\/sup>","60<sup>-1<\/sup>","30<sup>-1<\/sup>","90<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the simple interest rate percent per annum at which #1,000 accumulates to #1,240 in 3 years.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8%","7%","6%","5%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man invested #5000 for 9 months at 4%. What is the simple interest ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N220","N130","N150","N250"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If log<sub>3<\/sub>18+log<sub>3<\/sub>3-log<sub>3<\/sub>x&nbsp;= 3, find x.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","1","0","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Raila has 7 different posters to be hanged in her bedroom, living room, and kitchen. Assuming she has plans to replace at least a poster in each of the 3 rooms, how many choices does she have?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["49","170","210","21"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the first 18 terms of the series 3,6,9,....,36<\/strong><\/p>","options":["513","505","433","635"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The second term of a geometrics series is 4 while the fourth term is 16. Find the sum of the first five terms.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60","54","64","62"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the size of each interior angle of a 12-sided regular polygon ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["120<sup>-1<\/sup>","150<sup>-1<\/sup>","30<sup>-1<\/sup>","180<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A circle of perimeter 28cm is opened to form a square. What is the maximum possible area of the square ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["56cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","98cm<sup>-1<\/sup>","49cm<sup>-1<\/sup>","28cm<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A solid metal cube of side 3cm is placed in a rectangular tank of dimensions 3, 4 and&nbsp; 5cm. What volume of water can the tank now&nbsp; hold<\/strong><\/p>","options":["48cm","33cm<sup>3<\/sup>","60cm<sup>3<\/sup>","27cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The perpendicular bisector of a line XY is the locus of a point<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Whose distance from X is always twice its distance from Y","Whose distance from Y is always twice its distance from X","Which moves on the line XY","Which is equidistance from the points X and Y"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The midpoint of P (x,y) and Q (8,6) is (5,8). Find x and y.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2,10)","(2,8)","(2,12)","(2,6)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man walks 100m due West from a point X to Y,he then walks 100m due North to a point Z. Find the bearing of X from Z.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["195<sup>-1<\/sup>","135<sup>-1<\/sup>","225<sup>-1<\/sup>","045<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The derivative of (2x+1)(3x+1) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12x+1","6x+5","6x+1","12x+5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of four consecutive integers is 34. Find the least of these numbers.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","8","7","5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The nth term of a sequence is n<sup>2<\/sup> - 6n-4. Find the sum of the 3rd and 4th terms.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["24","23","-24","-25"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The binary operation is defined on the set of integers such that&nbsp;<em>p*q&nbsp;= pq+p-q.&nbsp;<\/em>Find 2*(3*4).<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","13","15","22"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A circular arc subtend angle 150<em><sup>o<\/sup><\/em> at the centre of a circle&nbsp; of radius 12cm. Calculate&nbsp; the area of the sec to r of the arc.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","60cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","120cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","150cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the volume of a cuboid of length 0.76cm,&nbsp; breadth 2.6 cm and height 0.82cm.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.92cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>","2.13cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.97cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.62cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man stands on a tree 150cm high and see a boat an angle of depression of 74<sup>0<\/sup>. Find the distance of the boat from the base of the tree.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["52cm","43cm","40cm","15cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If the eight number is added, athe mean becomes 112. Find the eight number.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the median of 2,3,7,3,4,5,8,9,9,4,5,3,4,2 and 5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the standard deviation of 2,3,8, 10 and 12.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.9","4.9","5.9","6.9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can the letters of the word TOTALITY be arranged ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6720","6270","6207","6027"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The locus of a point equidistant from the intersection of lines 3x - 7y + 7 = 0 and 4x - 6y + 1 = 0 is a<\/strong><\/p>","options":["line parallel to 7x+13y+8=0","circle","semicircle","bisector of the line 7x-13y+8=0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The gradient of the straight line joining the points P(5,-7) and Q(-2,-3) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2","2\/5","4\/-7","-2\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find dy\/dx if y=cos x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sinx","-sinx","tanx","-tanx"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If an eighth number is added, the mean becomes 112. Find the eight number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If an eighth number is added, the mean becomes 112. Find the eight number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the median 2,3,7,3,4,5,8,9,9,4,5,3,4,2,4 and 5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of 4,9,6,3,2,8,10 and 11<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","9","8","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the standard deviation of 2,3,8,10 and 12<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.9","4.9","5.9","6.9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate <sup>n+1<\/sup>C<sub>n-2<\/sub>&nbsp;if n=15<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3630","3360","1120","560"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The cost of renovating a 5m square room is N500. What is the cost of renovating 10m square room?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000","N2,500","N2000","N10,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The cost of renovating a 5m square room is N500. What is the cost of renovating 10m square room?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000","N2,500","N2000","N10,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the rate of change of the total surface area S of a sphere with respect to its radius<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8&pi;","16&pi;","10&pi;","14&pi;"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differentiate (cos&theta; +sin&theta;)<sup>2<\/sup> with respect to&nbsp;&theta;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2cos2?","2sin2?","-2cos2?","-2sin2?"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A binary operation * on the set of rational numbers is defined&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>x * y = (2x + x<sup>3<\/sup> - y<sup>3<\/sup>) \/ (x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup>)&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>find -1*2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","-11","8","-8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of values of x for which 7x&gt;3x+4<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x < 7\/4","x > 7\/4","7x < 4","-4x < 7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the standard deviation of the following data 7,8,9,10,11,12,13<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","10","11"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If W is the mode and Z is the median of the following set of numbers 2.4,2.1,1.6,2.6,2.6,3.7,2.1 and 2.6 then (3W, 2Z) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2.6,2.5)","(7.8,5.0)","(2.1,2.5)","(6.2,5.0)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A trapezium has two parallel sides of length 6cm and 8cm. If the area is 42cm<sup>2<\/sup>, find the distance between the parallel sides<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6cm","8cm","7cm","5cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The average of three numbers is 32<sub>5<\/sub>. If the sum of the numbers is 131<sub>4<\/sub>, find the third number in base 6<\/strong><\/p>","options":["43<sub>6<\/sub>","34<sub>6<\/sub>","23<sub>6<\/sub>","32<sub>6<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three times the second term plus the seventh term of an AP is equal to the twelfth term. Find the relationship between the first term and the common difference<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3a-2d =0","3a+2d = 0","3a+d = 0","3a-d = 0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fence of 36m is to be built to make three sides of a rectangular compound, the fourth side being a building. Find the possible lengths of the shorter side of the compound if the area enclosed is 160m<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["20m,10m","16m,8m","20m,16m","10m,8m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find dy\/dx if y = 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - sin2x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4x+2cosx","4x-2cos2x","4x-4cos2x","4x+4cos2x"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contains 4x First Bank ATM cards (2x-1), UBA Bank ATM cards and 3(x+1) Zenith Bank ATM cards. If the probability of picking a First Bank ATM is 2\/5; how many UBA Bank ATM cards are in the bag?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","8","9","20"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express the product of 0.000128 and 0.00125 in standard form&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.6x11<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-5<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-7<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-4<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If(2x-1)+1\/(2x-1)=4, find the value of 4x-4x+1\/(2x-1)<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["19","13","-13","-19"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student dropped an object from a building 100m high. If the height of the object object above after t seconds is 100-4.9t<sup>2<\/sup>m. How fast is it falling 3 seconds after it is dropped?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["14.7m\/sec","85.3m\/sec","29.4m\/sec","70.6m\/sec"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>An investor who received N6500.00 as some simple interest rate collected a total amount of N7,800.00 after four years. How much simple interest would he have collected after two years if he had invested N9,000.000?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000.00","N10000.00","N650.00","N900.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the sum of the roots of the equation 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5px + 8 =0 is five times the product of the roots, find the value of P<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-8","1\/8","8","-1\/8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If log<sub>10<\/sub>4=x, express log(12.5)<sup>3<\/sup> in terms of x&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4-3x","6x-2","4+3x","4(1-x)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area of the region enclosed by the curve y=2-x<sup>2<\/sup> and the line y=-x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/2","9","3","9\/2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify (log(xy<sup>2<\/sup>) - 2log x + log y\/x<sup>2<\/sup>) \/ (log (y\/x)<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>For 0&lt;x&lt;y<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-3","3","-1\/3","1\/3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify (2x<sup>3<\/sup> - x<sup>2<\/sup> - 13x - 6 = 2x + 1) \/ 2x + 1<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x-2)(x-3)","(x-2)(x+3)","(x+2)(x+3)","(x+2)(x-3)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The solution to the simultaneous equation 2x + y = 10 and 4x<sup>2<\/sup> - y<sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;= 140 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x=2, y= -6","x=2, y=6","x=6, y= -2","x=6, y=2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the circle which passes through the points (0,0) and (-1,2) and whose center lies on the line y-2x+1=0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x-1\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y-2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x+1\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x-2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate lim<sub>x-&gt;1<\/sub> (x<sup>2<\/sup>+x-2) \/ (x-1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0","3","2","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student pumps a ball and its volume increases at the rate of n(16-t<sup>2<\/sup>)cm<sup>3<\/sup> per second. If the initial volume is (11n)cm<sup>3<\/sup>, find the volume of the ball after 3 seconds<\/strong><\/p>","options":["28n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","68n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","39n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","50n cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Score&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 0&nbsp; &nbsp;1&nbsp; 2&nbsp; 3&nbsp; 4&nbsp; &nbsp; 5<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>No. of students 24&nbsp; 8&nbsp; 4&nbsp; 6&nbsp; 10&nbsp; 8<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The distribution above shows the scores of 60 students in a class test. What percentage of the students scored at least 3<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60%","36%","66%","40%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Subject Biology Chemistry Maths Physics<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Marks&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;95&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;2x+10&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; x&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 75<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>If the total mark obtained by a student is 300, what is the angle corresponding to the mark obtained in chemistry if the information is represented in a pie chart?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["120<sup>o<\/sup>","114<sup>o<\/sup>","48<sup>o<\/sup>","108<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A basket contains 5 MTN cards, 6 GLO cards, 3 9mobile cards and 3 Airtel cards. What is the probability that the card selected from the basket at random will be MTN or 9mobile cards?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/2","3\/4","1\/4","3\/5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the difference between 1.867551 correct to four significant figures and 1.867551 correct to four decimal places<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5x10<sup>-3<\/sup>","4x10<sup>-4<\/sup>","5xx10<sup>-4<\/sup>","10x10<sup>-3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of values of x satisfying the inequalities&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>2x - 5 &lt; 7 and 25 + 2x &gt; 15<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5<x<`-6","5<x<6","6<x<5","6<x<-5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the 8th term of an AP is three times the second term and the sum of the first three terms is 18, find the first term of the A.P<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","2","3","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum to infinity of the series 4+3+9\/4+27\/16+...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["16","16\/3","1","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the line which passes through (-2,1) and is perpendicular to the line 4x - 2y + 1 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2y - x - 4 = 0","2y + x = 0","2y - x = 0","y - 2y - 5 = 0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>An interest covered a distance of 44cm before reaching a point Q. Calculate POQ<\/strong><\/p>","options":["63<sup>o<\/sup>","12<sup>o<\/sup>","13<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first derivative of y = (2+3x)4 at x = -1 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12","-12","4","-4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The minimum value of (x) = x<sup>2<\/sup>-4x+5 in the interval(-1,1) is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","2","4","5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A company is to select three different handset phones from five different types of Nokia Brand and two different types of Samsung Brand. In how many ways can the company choose the handset, so as to include at least one Samsung brand?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","25","35","45"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"}]